Guide to the A. J. Antoon papers, 1961-1991
The New York Public Library. Billy Rose Theatre Division.
- Series V: Professional Productions, 1971-1991; 920942; 9 boxes (3.4 lin. ft.
  Subject to Fits,[1971] Written by Robert Montgomery, it was the first production Antoon directed for Joseph Papp. The work was based on Dostoievsky's The Idiot and opened February 14, 1971 at the Public Theater and ran for 127 performances. It moved to London's The Palace and was staged by the Royal Shakespeare Company featuring Ben Kingsley. The London performances ran from October 19 to December 11. The collection includes correspondence to and from Trevor Nunn, the artistic director for the Royal Shakespeare Company, a director's script, and a revised script.
  The Tale of Cymbeline,[1971] This Shakespeare play was the first NYSF production directed by Antoon at the outdoor Delacorte Theater in Central Park. The play opened August 12, 1971 and ran through the 29th. One of the actors, Sam Waterston, worked with Antoon a year later in Much Ado About Nothing. Included are production notes and director's script.
  Taming of the Shrew, [1990] The last show Antoon directed for The New York Shakespeare Festival. Set in the Old West, it starred Morgan Freeman and Tracey Ullman and was the opening play for the 1990 summer season of free Shakespeare at Central Park's Delacorte Theater. It ran from July 12 to July 22. Includes final script (June 1990), version C script (May 1990), rehearsal and performance calendar, and stage drawings.
  That Championship Season, [1972] Written by Jason Miller, it became the most successful play for Antoon as a stage director. A NYSF production, first performances were held at the Public Theater from May 2 to September 3, 1972. The play moved to the Booth Theatre on Broadway and opened September 14 and ran through April 21, 1974. The show featured Charles Durning, Paul Sorvino, and Richard Dysart. It earned Jason Miller the 1973 Pulitzer Prize. Antoon was handed three major theater awards--the Tony, the Drama Desk, and Drama Critics Circle awards. The show was later re-staged in Detroit in late 1973, and London in 1974 with Broderick Crawford. Two scripts are included, with an opening night invitation, and Antoon's contract.
  Trelawny of the 'Wells' ,[1975] The play by Sir Arthur Wing Pinero opened October 3, 1975 at the Vivian Beaumont Theater. Meryl Streep and Mandy Patinkin made their Broadway debuts in the show. An opening night card from actor John Lithgow is the only item included.
  Wild Oats, [1982] Original script by John O'Keeffe, it was adapted by Antoon and performed at the Santa Fe Festival Theatre, Santa Fe, New Mexico. The Wild West setting featured Kelsey Grammer in the lead and ran from June 28 to August 22, 1982. Contains an original script, annotated by Antoon, two adaptations, production notes and stage drawings.
  - The art of dining / Tina Howe, 1978; 920943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The art of dining / Tina Howe, 1979; 920944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The art of dining / Tina Howe, 1980; 920945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Dance of death / August Strindberg, 1975; 920946 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Dance of death / August Strindberg, 1976; 920947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Derelict / Robert Schenkkan, 1981; 920948 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Double cross / Gary Bohlke, 1988; 920949 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Double cross / Gary Bohlke, September 10, 1990; 920950 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Double cross / Gary Bohlke, September 25, 1990; 920951 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The effect of gamma rays on man-in-the-moon marigolds / Paul Zindel, 1977; 920952 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The effect of gamma rays on man-in-the-moon marigolds / Paul Zindel, 1978; 920953 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Genesis: music and miracles from the Medieval mystery plays / A.J. Antoon, 1989; 920954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Genesis: music and miracles from the Medieval mystery plays / A.J. Antoon, 1989; 920955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Genesis: music and miracles from the Medieval mystery plays / A.J. Antoon, 1988; 920956 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Genesis: music and miracles from the Medieval mystery plays / A.J. Antoon, 1988; 920957 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Genesis: music and miracles from the Medieval mystery plays / A.J. Antoon, 1985; 920958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Genesis: music and miracles from the Medieval mystery plays / A.J. Antoon, 1989; 920959 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The girl I left behind me / David Belasco, 1981; 920960 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The girl I left behind me / David Belasco, 1981; 920961 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The girl I left behind me / David Belasco, 1980; 920962 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The good doctor / Neil Simon, 1973; 920963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The good doctor / Neil Simon, 1973; 920964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - The good doctor / Neil Simon, 920965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The good doctor / Neil Simon, 920966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - A good life (Musical) / Stanley Silverman, 1986; 920967 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - A good life (Musical) / Stanley Silverman, 920968 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - A good life (Musical) / Stanley Silverman, 920969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - The house of blue leaves / John Guare, 1981; 920970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 1977; 920971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 920972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 920973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 920974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 1975; 920975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 920976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 920977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 920978 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - A life in the theatre / David Mamet, 1977; 920979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - A Midsummer night's dream / William Shakespeare, 1988; 920980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Much ado about nothing / William Shakespeare, 1973; 920981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Nasty rumors and final remarks / Susan Miller, 1978; 920982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Nasty rumors and final remarks / Susan Miller, 1979; 920983 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The palace of amateurs / John Faro PiRoman, 1982; 920984 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The palace of amateurs / John Faro PiRoman, 1982; 920985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The palace of amateurs / John Faro PiRoman, 1982; 920986 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The palace of amateurs (Screenplay) / John Faro PiRoman, 1983; 920987 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 1983; 920988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 1982; 920989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 1983; 920990 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 1982; 920991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 1983; 920992 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 1983; 920993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 1983; 920994 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 920995 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Sherlock's last case / Charles Marowitz, 1987; 920996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Sherlock's last case / Charles Marowitz, 1987; 920997 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Song of Singapore (Musical), 1989 / Erik Frandsen, 920998 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - South Pacific (Musical) / Richard Rodgers, 1986; 920999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - South Pacific (Musical) / Richard Rodgers, 1984; 921000 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - South Pacific (Musical) / Richard Rodgers, 1986; 921001 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - South Pacific (Musical) / Richard Rodgers, 1986; 921002 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Story theater / Paul Sills, 1971; 921003 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Subject to fits / Robert Montgomery, 1971; 921004 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Subject to fits / Robert Montgomery, 1971; 921005 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Subject to fits / Robert Montgomery, 1971; 921006 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Taming of the shrew / William Shakespeare, 1990; 921007 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Taming of the shrew / William Shakespeare, 1990; 921008 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Taming of the shrew / William Shakespeare, 1990; 921009 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - That championship season / Jason Miller, 1972; 921010 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - That championship season / Jason Miller, 1972; 921011 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - That championship season / Jason Miller, 19972; 921012 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - That championship season / Jason Miller, 1972; 921013 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - That championship season / Jason Miller, 1972; 921014 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Cymbeline / William Shakespeare, 1971; 921015 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Cymbeline / William Shakespeare, 1971; 921016 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Trelawney of the 'Wells' / Sir Arthur Wing Pinero, 1975; 921017 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Wild oats / John O'Keeffe, 1982; 921018 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Wild oats / John O'Keeffe, 1982; 921019 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Wild oats / John O'Keeffe, 1982; 921020 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Wild oats / John O'Keeffe, 1982; 921021 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Series VI: Production Clippings, 1971-1990; 921022; 1 box (.4 lin. ft.
  This series includes press clippings and reviews from professional productions directed by Antoon.
  - The art of dining / Tina Howe, 1979; 921023 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Dance of death / August Strindberg, 1974; 921024 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Derelict / Robert Schenkkan, 1982; 921025 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - The effect of gamma rays on man-in-the-moon marigolds / Paul Zindel, 1978; 921026 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Genesis: music and miracles for a new age (Musical) / Michael Ward, 1988; 921027 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The girl I left behind me / David Belasco, 1981; 921028 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The good doctor / Neil Simon, 1973; 921029 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - A good life (Musical) / Stanley Silverman, 1986; 921030 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The house of blue leaves / John Guare, 1981; 921031 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 1977; 921032 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - A life in the theatre / David Mamet, 1987; 921033 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Clippings / A.J. Antoon, 1973; 921034 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Midsummer night's dream / William Shakespeare, 1988; 921035 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Much ado about nothing / William Shakespeare, 1972; 921036 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Nasty rumors and final remarks / Susan Miller, 1979; 921037 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - The rink (Musical) / John Kander, 1984; 921038 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Sherlock's last case / Charles Marowitz, 1987; 921039 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Subject to fits / Robert Montgomery, 1971; 921040 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Cymbeline / William Shakespeare, 1971; 921041 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Taming of the shrew / William Shakespeare, 1990; 921042 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - That championship season / Jason Miller, 1972; 921043 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Trelawney of the 'Wells' / Sir Arthur Wing Pinero, 1975; 921044 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Wild oats / John O'Keeffe, 1982; 921045 (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Series VII: Writings, 1962-1985; 921046; 5 boxes (1.6 lin. ft.
  The series contains short stories, plays, and screenplays written by Antoon. Except for the short story A Thing Like That For, none of these works were ever published or produced.
  Arranged by sub-series and then by title.
  - Sub-series 1-Writings-Amateur, ca. 1962-1969; 921047; 1 box (.2 lin. ft.
    These short stories and plays are arranged in chronological order and were done by Antoon while at Shadowbrook Jesuit Seminary (1962-1965), Boston College (1965-1968), and Yale (1968-1970). He received an honorable mention in 1968 for the short story A Thing Like That For in the Atlantic Monthly's 47th Annual Creative Writing Contest.
    - Untitled short story / A.J. Antoon, 1962; 921048 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - The shadow on the earth / Owen Francis Dudley, 1962; 921049 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - White Snow and the seven tramps / A.J. Antoon, 1964; 921050 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - When owls do cry / A.J. Antoon, 1965; 921051 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - A thing like that for / A.J. Antoon, 1965; 921052 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - A thing like that for / A.J. Antoon, 1968; 921053 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Boston College writings / A.J. Antoon, 1967; 921054 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Today I hugged and kicked a tree / A.J. Antoon, 1965; 921055 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - But sparrows never migrate in the fall / A.J. Antoon, 1968; 921056 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Shoemaker's holiday (Musical) / A.J. Antoon, 1968; 921057 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Tadtarin / A.J. Antoon, 1969; 921058 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Sub-series 2-Writings-Professional, 1975-1985; 921059; 4 boxes (1.4 lin. ft.
    Snow White, [1975-1981] This screenplay was written by Antoon with the final draft completed in 1978. The story was not based on the Walt Disney cartoon but on the original Grimm tale. He considered well-known actors to play the leads such as Meryl Streep as the Queen, but the motion picture was never produced due to lack of interest and money. Box 18 includes the final draft from 1978 and five drafts. Box 19 includes handwritten drafts, conceptual drawings and photographs of characters, legal/agency correspondence (1978-1980), and general correspondence (1976-1981), some from producer Charles Fries, and a letter from actor Albert Finney rejecting a role.
    Hotheads,[1979] Author Gen LeRoy and Antoon collaborated on this screenplay that was based on her novel. The box contains four drafts of the screenplay, the final version written in 1979, and legal agreements.
    Treasure Island,[1985] This musical written by Antoon was based on the Robert Louis Stevenson tale and also based on a musical of the same title by Gary William Friedman (lyrics by Will Holt, book by Sherman Yellen). The show was booked to open in the summer of 1985 with Antoon as director, but it lost the star Telly Savalas for unknown reasons. Included are notes, a complete and annotated draft, three incomplete drafts, scene breakdowns, and the first draft of the musical by Friedman. Also included is a letter that Antoon wrote to Charles Hunt expressing the feeling that the people involved were taking advantage of his generosity.
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1978; 921060 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1978; 921061 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1978; 921062 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1976; 921063 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1976; 921064 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1976; 921065 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1976; 921066 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1976; 921067 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1976; 921068 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1976; 921069 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Snow White (Screenplay) / A.J. Antoon, 1976; 921070 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Hotheads (Screenplay), 1979 / Gen LeRoy, 921071 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Hotheads (Screenplay), 1979 / Gen LeRoy, 921072 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Hotheads (Screenplay), 1979 / Gen LeRoy, 921073 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Hotheads (Screenplay), 1979 / Gen LeRoy, 921074 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Hotheads (Screenplay), 1979 / Gen LeRoy, 921075 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Hotheads (Screenplay), 1979 / Gen LeRoy, 921076 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Treasure Island (Musical) / A.J. Antoon, 1985; 921077 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Treasure Island (Musical) / A.J. Antoon, 1985; 921078 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Treasure Island (Musical) / A.J. Antoon, 1985; 921079 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Treasure Island (Musical) / A.J. Antoon, 1985; 921080 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Treasure Island (Musical) / A.J. Antoon, 1985; 921081 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Series VIII: Proposed Productions, 197?-1985; 921082
  Ain't No Mountain High Enough, [1980] This was a treatment for a musical based on the story of a black Vietnam War veteran returning to civilian life. Folder also includes a popular song list and notes on the show.
  The Dreamland Park Dance Marathon Contest,[1983] With music and lyrics by Paul Katz, this suggested musical based on dance marathon contests during the Depression would have been directed by Antoon.
  Included are two copies of the proposal and a note from Antoon's mother who was excited by the concept.Lucy: The Bittersweet Life of Lucille Ball [no date] The idea by Joe Morella and Edward Z. Epstein was to write a musical based on the making of the television comedy I Love Lucy. Included are notes and possible story line.
  Miracle Plays,[1985] This concept script and materials about Old Testament Medieval Miracle Plays were sent to Joseph Papp in 1985 and later developed into the New York Shakespeare Festival production of Antoon's Genesis. Also included is the grant application Antoon filed with the Guggenheim Memorial Foundation to get funding for the plays.
  Theophilus North,[197?] Antoon pitched this idea of a six-part series for PBS based on the novel by Thorton Wilder.
  1 box (.2 lin. ft.)
  - Ain't no mountain high enough (Musical) / A.J. Antoon, 1980; 921083 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - The dreamland park dance marathon contest (Musical) / Paul Katz, 1983; 921084 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Lucy: the bittersweet life of Lucille Ball (Musical) / Joe Morella, 921085 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Miracle plays / A.J. Antoon, 1985; 921086 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Miracle plays / A.J. Antoon, 1985; 921087 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Theophilus North treatment / A.J. Antoon, 921088 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Series IX: Miscellaneous Scripts, ca. 1972-1986; 921089; 1 box (.4 lin. ft.
  Hard Times: A Look at the Depression Years, [ca. 1972] Attributed to Jason Miller, the script is based on the book by Studs Turkel, Antoon was to direct. Includes three pages of photocopied notes.
  Magic Barrel, [no date] No author is attributed to the script. It is based on the short story by Bernard Malamud.
  McElroy, [no date] Probably Antoon's handwritten concept outline for a script.
  The Oldest Profession,[1986] Included are the script, screenplay, and various re-writes by author Paula Vogel. Antoon was slated to direct the motion picture.
  Stage Door, [1980] This musical by Dan Goggin (book and lyrics by Robert Lorick) was based on the 1936 play of the same title by Edna Ferber and George S. Kaufman. Antoon was chosen to direct the show but Goggin withdrew in July 1981 citing "artistic differences" with Antoon. Included with the completed script are notes to Antoon from producer Karen Kantor, legal agreements regarding the production, and a color photocopy of the program cover.
  Two Minute Warning,[no date] Jason Miller wrote this screenplay about life in a Pennsylvania strip-mining town. Miller also wrote the play
  That Championship Season which Antoon directed.
  Arranged by title.
  - Hard times: a look at the Depression years, 1972; 921090 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Magic barrel, 921091 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - McElroy, 921092 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - The oldest profession / Paula Vogel, 1986; 921093 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - The oldest profession (Screenplay) / Paula Vogel, 1986; 921094 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Stage door (Musical) / Dan Goggin, 1980; 921095 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Stage door (Musical) / Dan Goggin, 1981; 921096 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Stage door (Musical) / Dan Goggin, 1980; 921097 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Two minute warning (Screenplay) / Jason Miller, 921098 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Series X: Original Art Work, 1972-1986; 921099; 1 box (flat file, 3 lin. ft.
  This series contains original art work from Antoon productions:
  1972 Much Ado About Nothing--collage possibly done by Antoon, was later used as a pattern for the stage backdrop.
  1973 The Good Doctor--2 water color drawings of the father and son, done by Tony Walton, scene and costume designer.
  1974 Dance of Death--water color of the set by set designer Santo Loquasto.
  1977 King of Hearts--Two sheets of the logotype.
  1981 The Girl I Left Behind Me--5 set design drawings.
  1982 The Palace of Amateurs--3 set design drawings on one large sheet of paper.
  1986 A Good Life--water color of the program cover? by Thomas Seaman.
  198? --Design boards for Antoon's stationary.
  - The palace of amateurs / John Faro PiRoman, 1982; 921100 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - The girl I left behind me / David Belasco, 1981; 921101 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - The girl I left behind me / David Belasco, 1981; 921102 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - The good doctor / Neil Simon, 1973; 921103 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - The good doctor / Neil Simon, 1973; 921104 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - A good life (Musical) / Stanley Silverman, 1986; 921105 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Dance of death / August Strindberg, 1974; 921106 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Much ado about nothing / William Shakespeare, 1972; 921107 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - King of hearts (Musical) / Peter Link, 1977; 921108 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Personal ephemera / A.J. Antoon, 1980; 921109 (Box 24, Folder 10)